BRUNO C. M. BARRETO

Redmond, WA · 425-301-0338 · bruno@barreto.us · LinkedIn · Portfolio

SUMMARY

I am a data scientist with a background in bioengineering who helps design future-proof and scalable machine learning solutions for unsolved data prediction and parsing problems. My academic research experience combined with my proficiency in Azure, Java, Python, and SQL, positions me as a strong candidate for opportunities in cloud-based data science.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Python - SQL - Java - MATLAB

CODING: Pandas - Numpy - Scikit-Learn - Scipy - Matplotlib - Seaborn

MACHINE LEARNING: Regression - Classification - Natural Language Processing - Neural Networks **SOFTWARE**: Github - Microsoft Azure - Slack - Jupyter Notebooks - Google Colab - Microsoft Office

DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS

DEEP LEARNING IMAGE CLASSIFIER, DATA SCIENTIST

04/2022 - 06/2022

• Developed a model in Python to automatically classify images into 10 distinct categories using a trained convolutional neural network with 90% accuracy in classification.

NERVE TISSUE REGENERATION MODEL, DATA SCIENTIST

05/2021 - 06/2021

• Developed a model of peripheral nerve regeneration for neuroscientists that reduced growth factor conduit testing times by 100x using COMSOL Multiphysics.

TURBO GLYCOLYSIS PID CONTROLLER, BIOINFORMATICIAN

04/2022 - 06/2022

• Created a PID controller in Python and MATLAB for ATP production in an unstable turbo glycolysis bioreactor that improved reactor settling times by 80% and made reactions stable.

AMES HOUSING PRICE ESTIMATOR, DATA SCIENTIST

• Created a machine learning model to automatically assign appropriate house prices for realtors in Ames, lowa using a linear regression trained on local tax data, resulting in a model capable of accounting for 92% of variance in house prices.

ACCIDENT SEVERITY PREDICTOR NLP, DATA SCIENTIST

 Developed a model that can predict flight accident severity from a formal report with 90% accuracy and determine that improper installation and maintenance of airframe components was a key cause of high lethality

EXPERIENCE

DATA SCIENCE FELLOW, GENERAL ASSEMBLY, REMOTE

10/2022 - 02/2023

Successfully completed 500+ hours of expert-led instruction in data exploration, machine learning, data visualization and hands-on learning of Data Science fundamentals and the industry's most in demand technologies.

CAPSTONE STUDENT, NANOSTRING, REDMOND, WA

01/2022 - 06/2022

 GEOMX SUSTAINABLE REAGENT PROJECT - Reducing operating costs for the GeoMx Digital Spatial Profiler by altering reagent bottle structure and modifying device software to intelligently monitor fluid requirements, resulting in a 20% drop in reagent costs.

EDUCATION

Certificate, Data Science, General Assembly

B.S. in Bioengineering w/ Data Science, University of Washington, Seattle, WA

Certificate, Azure Data Science Associate (DP-100)

Certificate, Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900)

10/2022 - 02/2023

09/2018 - 07/2022

07/2022 - 09/2022

06/2022 - 07/2022